# CURRICULUM VITAE

# Iegor Riepin

#### Research fellow at BTU CS

My research focuses on the mathematical modelling of energy markets. I have experience in working with various modelling approaches and empirical applications. Broader areas of interest include optimization theory, energy auctions, and complex system modelling in general.

Academic page | GitHub | LinkedIn

T: +4917698442432

E: <u>iegor.riepin@b-tu.de</u>



## Work experience

2014.11 – present	Research fellow
2021.10 – present	Energy Systems Modelling group lead
	Brandenburg University of Technology (BTU CS), Germany
	Chair of Energy Economics
2019.09 - 2019.10	Visiting researcher
	University of Victoria (UVic), Canada
	Institute for Integrated Energy Systems
2013.10 - 2014.09	Student assistant
	Chair of Energy Economics, BTU CS
2013.09 - 2013.10	Intern
2019.09 2019.10	DIW Berlin, Institute for Economic Research, Germany
	Department: Energy, Transportation, Environment
	- $        -$

#### Education

2014.11 - present	PhD candidate in energy economics: mathematical modelling of
	energy markets   Supervision: <u>Prof. Felix Müsgens</u>   BTU CS
2012 - 2014	M.Sc. (Hon) in Power Engineering BTU CS, Germany   Final grade: 1.2
2008 - 2012	B.Sc. (Hon) in Heat Power Engineering ZSEA, Ukraine   Final grade: 4.98 (5)

## Completed & ongoing projects at BTU CS

2021 - ongoing	TransHyDE: System analysis of transport solutions for green
$Project\ acquisition$	hydrogen
$and\ supervision$	Funding: BMBF (Federal Ministry of Education and Research)
	Cooperation: >30 partners   Project web page
2017	Design of auctions for market premia for onshore wind generation:
$Research\ fellow$	theoretical and experimental testing. Cooperation: CERGE-EI.
	Summary
2016	Strategy 2020: modelling of forward prices for natural gas in
$Research\ fellow$	European gas markets. Funding: industry partner. Cooperation: <u>r2b</u>
	energy consulting GmbH
2014 - 2016	Fundamental gas market analysis in a context of the German
$Research\ fellow$	<b>energy transition process.</b> Funding: gas trading utility.
	Cooperation: r2b energy consulting GmbH. <u>Summary</u>

## Peer-reviewed journal articles

Research articles #1, #5, #6, #7 form my PhD thesis.

1. European gas infrastructure expansion planning: an adaptive robust optimization approach

Riepin, I., Schmidt, M., Baringo, L., Müsgens, F., Working paper at Optimization Online (2021)

In review | Code

2. Risk aversion in flexible electricity markets

Möbius, T., Riepin, I., Müsgens, F., Adriaan H. van der Weijde *In review* | <u>Code</u>
Working paper at arXiv (2021): arxiv.org/abs/2110.04088

Working paper at arXiv (2021). <u>arXiv.org/abs/2110.04000</u>

Grok it and use it: Teaching energy systems modeling
Riepin, I., Sgarciu, S., Bernecker, M., Möbius, T., Müsgens, F.

In review | Course GitHub

4. Policy choices and outcomes for the global competitive procurement of offshore wind

Jansen, M., Beiter, P., Riepin, I., Müsgens, F. Juarez Guajardo-Fajardo, V., Staffell, I., Bulder, B., Kitzing, L.

 $In\ review$ 

5. Applied Energy (2021). Combining uncertainty with electricity and gas sector coupling – worth the effort?

Riepin, I., Möbius, T., Müsgens, F.

DOI: <u>10.1016/j.apenergy.2020.116363</u> | <u>Code</u>

Working paper at arXiv (2020): arxiv.org/abs/2008.07221

6. Nature Energy (2020). Offshore wind competitiveness in mature markets without subsidy.

Jansen, M., Staffell, I., Kitzing, L., Quoilin, S., Wiggelinkhuizen, E., Bulder, B., Riepin, I., Müsgens, F.

DOI:  $\underline{10.1038/s41560-020-0661-2} \mid \underline{\text{Code}} \mid \underline{\text{Supplementary data}} \mid \underline{\text{Nature Energy News}}$  & Views | Media coverage:  $\underline{118}$  news stories from 116 outlets

7. The Energy Journal (2022). Seasonal flexibility in the European natural gas market. [preprint]

Riepin, I., Müsgens, F.

DOI: 10.5547/01956574.43.1.irie | Code

Cambridge Working Papers in Economics (2019)

DOI: <u>10.17863/CAM.43923</u> | <u>Abstract</u> | <u>Non-Technical Summary</u> | <u>PDF</u>

### (Peer-reviewed) conference articles

8. IEEE EEM (2020). Regret analysis of investment decisions under uncertainty in an integrated energy system.

Möbius, T., Riepin, I.

DOI: 10.1109/EEM49802.2020.9221935

9. IEEE EEM (2018). Integrated electricity and gas market modeling – effects of gas demand uncertainty.

Riepin, I., Möbius, T., Müsgens, F.

DOI: <u>10.1109/EEM.2018.8469790</u> | <u>preprint version</u> | <u>Video</u>

10. IEEE EEM (2018). Is offshore already competitive? Analyzing German offshore wind auctions.

Müsgens, F., Riepin, I.

DOI: 10.1109/EEM.2018.8469851 | preprint version | Video

11. IEEE EEM (2016). Modelling of world LNG market development: focus on US investments and supplies.

Montenegro, R., Riepin, I., Hauser, P.

DOI: <u>10.1109/EEM.2016.7521361</u>

## Other publications

12. CarbonBrief (2020). The era of 'negative-subsidy' offshore wind power has almost arrived

Riepin, I., Jansen, M., Staffell, I., Müsgens, F.

Guest post

13. e|m|w.trends (2020). Offshore-Windenergie - subventionsfrei? Müsgens, F. and Riepin, I.

Guest post

14. Oxford Institute for Energy Studies & BTU CS (2015). A note on climate policy negotiations at the threshold of COP-21 in Paris.

Müsgens, F., Poudineh, R., Riepin, I. PDF

- 15. ZSEA (2011). Usage of solar energy for heating service and domestic water heating.
  - Riepin, I. | VII all-Ukrainian scientific conference. Vol. 2, pp. 78 83.
- 16. ZSEA (2011). Ukrainian market prospects in the field of alternative energy sources.
  - Riepin, I. | The annual conference for graduate students. pp. 186 192.

#### Public talks

- 1. European Natural Gas Infrastructure Expansion Planning: An Adaptive Robust Optimization Approach
  - PDF | Code @ EWI Cologne & BTU CS Research seminars 2021
  - PDF | Code @ European Conference on Operational Research, Athens, Greece, 2021
- 2. The costs of ignoring uncertainty and the value of perfect information: a toy model.
  - PDF | Code @ Doctoral seminar, BTU CS, 2019
- 3. Robust optimization of electricity system expansion.
  - PDF | Code @ University of Victoria, Canada, 2019
- 4. Economic impacts of uncertainty in integrated electricity and gas markets.
  - PDF @ 30<sup>th</sup> European Conference on Operational Research, Dublin, Ireland, 2019
- 5. Integrated electricity and gas market modelling effects of gas demand uncertainty.
  - PDF @ EEM2018 Conference, Lodz, Poland, 2018
  - PDF @ PhD seminar Cottbus-Leipzig-Dresden, 2018
- 6. Integration of electricity and gas market models.
  - PDF @ Energy modelling seminar, IER, Universität Stuttgart, 2018
- 7. Application of non-linear and complementarity problems for natural gas market modelling.
  - PDF @ Research seminar with chair of Mathematical Economics, BTU CS, 2017
  - PDF @ Internal research seminar, BTU CS, 2016
- 8. Natural Gas Storages in Competition with Alternative Flexibility Sources.

PDF @ 39th IAEE International Conference, Bergen, Norway, 2016

PDF @ PhD seminar Cottbus-Leipzig-Dresden, 2016

9. Prospects for Shale Gas Exploration in Europe: Ongoing Experience.

PDF @ 38<sup>th</sup> IAEE International Conference, Antalya, Turkey, 2015

### Teaching experience

WS17/18 - WS19/20	Energy Systems Modelling (course development, selected
	lectures, tutorials, supervision of student projects)
	Lecture: Prof. Dr. Felix Müsgens   Course GitHub page
$\mathrm{WS}14/15-\mathrm{SS}2018$	Power System Economics 1 & 2 (tutorials)
	Lecture: Prof. Dr. Felix Müsgens and Prof. Dr. Stefan Zundel

## Scholarships & awards

2017.11 - 2019.10	Postgraduate scholarship, BTU CS (Promotionsstipendium des Landes Brandenburg, GradV)
2014	Rheinstahl foundation study scholarship (Master degree)
2013	STIBET study scholarship, DAAD (Master degree)
2010	Zaporizhia city administration scholarship (Bachelor degree)

## (Selected) technical skills and languages

Mathematical	GAMS (project-related use, research and teaching)
modelling &	Python (research and hobby projects)
programming	Git (version control)
Languages	English (fluent)   German (C1 certificate)
	Ukrainian & Russian (native fluent)

#### References

- 1. <u>Prof. Felix Müsgens</u> | academic supervisor and chairholder (~6 years of work together)
- 2. Thomas Möbius | colleague & co-author (~6 years)
- 3. <u>Taimyra Batz Lineiro</u> | colleague (~3 years)
- 4. <u>Maximilian Bernecker</u> | colleague & co-author (~2 years)
- 5. Roland Cuhna Montenegro | former colleague & co-author (~2 years)

As a hobby, I do enjoy astrophotography.